DHARUN NISHANTH S

Application Developer

Passionate and self-motivated programmer curious about learning and working on life-changing technologies to solve various problems. Being worked as a developer, I can contribute something to the application throughout its lifecycle. Always up for exploring new roles and challenges.

Work Experience

Cognizant

07/2020 - 10/2021

Programmer Analyst

Chennai, Tamil Nadu

- resolved dependency (jar) vulnerabilities and open redirect issue for 2 applications

Client: A leading American bank

- developed a desktop application to check the MQ connection
- enabled and customized CI/CD pipelines for projects in Gitlab
- created a bash script to collect user, browser information from application logs
- migrated 4 applications from brownfield to greenfield.

07/2019 - 07/2020

Programmer Analyst Trainee

- was part of rewriting a trading application
- developed the decommissioning UI for the application

02/2019 - 03/2019, 05/2019

Full Stack Developer Intern

- Developed 2 functionalities and the UI of an Airport Management System web app as part of internship project

Skills

Languages	Frameworks	Tools	Certifications
Java 8 Bash Script SQL HTML CSS YAML	Spring MVC • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •	Eclipse Gitlab CI/CD Maven Jenkins Ansible Veracode	• AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentisals

Education

2015-2019

Karpagam Institute of Technology, Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu

- B.E- Electrical & Electronics Engineering
- 7.35 CGPA

Personal Information



Books/Audio Books, Singing, Drawing/Painting



Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu, India



sdharunnishanth@gmail.com





